### **CURRICULUM VITAE**

Name Mallikarjun Tirlapur

Date of birth **22.04.1988** 

Telephone +919740003234

E-mail <u>tirlapurmallikarjun@gmail.com</u>
Website <u>https://mallikarjuntirlapur.github.io/</u>

Address #28, 1st B Main Road, Mohan Kumar Nagar, Yeshwanthpur,

560022, Bengaluru, India

## **OBJECTIVE**

A Challenging position that allows me to continuously engage with and adapt to new technologies. I am committed to leveraging my skills and expertise to drive innovation and contribute to the continued success of the organization.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# **Embedded Security Software Developer,**

01.02.2016 -

### Staff Embedded Software Developer,

### Senior Staff Embedded Software Developer

# Infineon Technologies AG, Augsburg / Bengaluru.

- Expert in embedded secure software development, developing Java Card Operating System in a scrum team.
- Designed and developed a high-performance and secure Java Card Virtual Machine in native embedded C.
- Developed threat models and secure coding patterns, implemented security countermeasures against attacks.
- Developed well documented I2C low-level drivers and JC API native interfaces.
- Designed and implemented memory management algorithms for handling native and java objects in memory.
- Conceptualized and successfully led a team in the development of a Java Card binary linker tool.
- Implemented over **50** Java Card Virtual Machine bytecodes, enhancing the platform's functionality and security.
- Defined memory layout for the OS and architected memory access permissions by programming MPU.
- Automated MPU configurations there by reducing developer effort by 50%.
- Configured ARM TrustZone for enabling secure world for OS and non-secure world for sandbox applications.
- Proposed and implemented over 10+ innovative ideas that significantly reduced code footprint by ~40 KB, resulting in substantial improvements to system performance.
- Established code review standards within scrum team to ensure high-quality and secure coding practices.
- Developed robust white box and black box tests to enhance software quality assurance.
- Developed automation tools using python scripting language to streamline daily software CI process.
- Developed java card applets, unit tests and fixed bugs.
- Knowledge of Specifications: Oracle JCVM, JCRE, JCAPI.
- Patent Filed:
  - 1. "A method of improving Java card VM performance of the java card product." (increased by 150%)
  - 2. "Alias for package-info in import component of CAP file." (90% package-info footprint saving)

## **Embedded Developer**

01.11.2015 - 31-01-2016

# COBI-Connected Biking for everyone, Frankfurt.

- Developed tasks on FreeRTOS, programming PWM for driving RGB channels of LED light of the bike.
- Bug fixing, test case implementation.
- Procured knowledge in CAN bus e-bike driver development.

## **Master Thesis**

01.04.2015 - 30.09.2015

# **KUKA Roboter GmbH, R&D Technology Development, Augsburg.**

Research Topic: A framework for non-expert robot programming facilitated by a self-localizing smart device.

Objective: A smart device (Project Tango Smartphone) equipped with high-end sensing capabilities facilitates the

**Objective:** A smart device (Project Tango Smartphone) equipped with high-end sensing capabilities facilitates the programming of industrial robots in the field of logistic tasks such as pick-and-place and packaging.

- Developed an android app to publish on touch 2D pixel coordinates.
- Developed algorithms in C++ on ROS platform to locate objects.

• Developed a base station program for processing images using computer vision state-of-the-art algorithm APIs and teaching KUKA LBR iiwa 7 R800 robot.

<u>Internship</u> 01.09.2014 – 28.02.2015

KUKA Roboter GmbH, R&D Technology Development, Augsburg.

Research Project: Developing pick-and-place robotic applications using Project Tango Smartphone on ROS (Robot Operating System) platform.

- Developed an android app from scratch to parse super frames for depth & RGB images and publish live images into ROS network over wireless network (Wi-Fi).
- Developed 2D to 3D transformation algorithm.

# <u>Application Engineer</u> 05.07.2010 – 19.08.2013

### Microchip Technology Private Ltd (INDIA), Bangalore.

- Post-silicon validation of PIC microcontroller peripherals by writing various tests in C.
- Developed automated microcontroller characterization test system using LabVIEW.
- Developed magnetic stripe reader prototype for customers.
- Answering internal and external customer queries.

## **EDUCATION**

| CONTION                   |   |
|---------------------------|---|
| Hochschule Darmstadt,     | Master's in electrical engineering  |
| Germany                   | System Design (C++ & UML), Technical Project Management, Design and Test      |
| Sep 2013 - Feb 2016       | of Microelectronic Systems, Complex Digital Architectures, Advanced Feedback  |
|                           | Control, Advanced Automation, and Advanced Robotics.                          |
|                           |   |
| The National Institute Of | Bachelor of Engineering in Electronics and Communications Engineering         |
| Engineering, Mysore       | Basic and advanced Mathematics, C, C++, Logic Design, Image processing,       |
| Sep 2006 - June 2010      | Electronic Circuits and Design, Digital Signal Processing, Analog and Digital |
|                           | Communication, Microcontrollers, Microprocessors. Embedded Systems            |
|                           |   |

### SKILLS

General: Leadership, Requirement Analysis, Design, Architecture, Secure Software Development, Debugging, Testing

**Operating Systems:** Java Card OS, FreeRTOS, and Embedded Linux concepts.

**Programming Languages:** C, C++, Python, Java, C#, Assembly. **Microcontrollers & Processors:** ARM Cortex-M/A, PIC microcontrollers.

Microcontroller fundamentals: MPU, MMU, Timers, PWM, DMA, WDT, ADC, DAC.

Communication Buses: SPI, I2C, RS-232, and CAN.

IDEs: Keil uVision, Eclipse, VS Code, Visual Studio, Android Studio, MPLAB 8, and MPLAB X.

**Software tools:** ARM Toolchain, JavaCard Toolchain, MS Office Tools, Git, Doxygen, BitBucket, Jenkins, LabVIEW. **Lab Equipments:** Agilent &Tektronix Oscilloscope, Function generator, Digital multi-meters, DC Power supply,

Thermonics, Soldering.

Languages: English & Hindi (native proficiency), German (B1), and Kannada (mother tongue).

### VOLUNTEERING

- Member of Toastmasters Club
- Teacher at eVidyaloka(not-for-profit organisation) Trust

## Personal Traits

- Willing to learn new technologies.
- Self-motivated.
- Able to understand work responsibility and follow accordingly.
- Good resource management and a self-starter.

#### HOBBIES

Yoga, Badminton, Biking and Hiking.